# **POOJAN PATEL**

### **Profile**

I'm a Software Developer located in India. I have a serious passion for animations and creating intuitive, dynamic user experiences. I have worked with Frontend as well as Backend languages.

With a strong emphasis on "Progressive Enhancement", I look for creative ways to push the boundaries of website's code without compromising on browser support.

I'm determined to advance in my job and pick up new skills in order to keep up with the latest developments in technology and to help the company succeed.

# **Professional Experience**

# **Intern,** *TechnoGuide Infosoft Pvt. Ltd.* □

As a Frontend and Backend Developer, I've implemented the development of the VISA CRM system, a consultancy platform designed to assist students, faculty, and counselors in their study abroad journeys.

05/2023 – 06/2023 Anand, Gujarat

### Modules implemented:

- (i) Student Module: I've crafted the user-friendly interface for students, making it easy for them to access crucial information and check their VISA application status hassle-free.
- (ii) Counselor Module: I've worked on the Counselor Module, empowering counselors to provide expert guidance to students, including college recommendations and tailored advice.
- (iii) Admin Module: I've also contributed to the Admin Module, ensuring smooth system management and enhancing the user experience for administrators.

**Intern,** *KERYAR* □

Implemented the development of Salon Management Website to automate the products and services provided by the salon.

05/2022 – 07/2022 Anand, Gujarat

#### **Key Features:**

Our Salon Management Website offers a range of essential features, including:

- (1) Product Management: Effortlessly add and manage salon products and supplies.
- (2) Services Listing: Maintain a comprehensive list of services offered.
- (3) Invoice Generation: Streamline billing and invoice generation for clients.

Additional features, which I cannot disclose due to confidentiality.

### **Projects**

# **VISA CRM,** Automate the VISA Consultancy

The goal is to automate the whole VISA consultancy Program.

- --> It is developed based on CodeIgniter (PHP) and Django.
- --> It provides features like Visa & College Application Details. It also recommends colleges according to country in which you are going to study or settle. There are many features of this project but as it is company confidentiality I cannot disclose. It is still under development cycle.

#### **Django Authentication,** Secure User Management Made Easy

The goal of the project is to learn the customize authentication of Login and Signup.

--> It is developed based on Django, MySQL, Bootstrap & HTML/CSS.

06/2023 - present

05/2023

--> It provides the authentication of Login form fields such as name, email & password.

User Registration: Allow users to create accounts with a few simple steps, collecting

essential information.

Login and Logout: Provide a secure login system with session management for a

smooth user experience.

# **Certificates**

The Web Developer Bootcamp 2023 ☑

Advanced understanding of Frontend & Backend Applications

JavaScript Essentials ☑
Basic Understanding of
Fundamentals of JavaScript

#### **Skills**

HTML CSS

Experienced Experienced

JavaScript AngularJS Experienced Beginner

ReactJS Codelgniter

Skillful Skillful

**Django**Beginner
Beginner

**NodeJs**Skillful
Beginner

### **Education**

**B.Tech, Computer Engineering,** CSPIT, CHARUSAT 05/2020 – present

Changa, Gujarat

Anand, Gujarat

Anand, Gujarat

**Higher Secondary (CBSE),** *Kendriya Vidhyalaya* 04/2008 – 05/2020

Secondary (CBSE), Kendriya Vidhyalaya 04/2008 – 05/2020

91.8 %

# Languages

Gujarati English Hindi

Full working Proficiency Highly Proficient in Speaking and Full working proficiency Writing